[Music]
[音乐]
alright let's get started good morning
好吧，让我们开始早安
welcome to the session on reactive
欢迎参加反应式会议
programming in Java my name is Venkat
Java语言编程，我叫Venkat
Subramanyam we're going to talk about
Subramanyam我们将要讨论
reactive programming in general and then
反应式编程，然后
we'll talk about some examples how it
我们将讨论一些例子
works so let's get started I want to
有效，所以让我们开始吧，我想
first talk about reactive programming
首先谈一下反应式编程
itself so the first question I will
本身，所以我的第一个问题
start off with is the question why yet
首先要问的是为什么
another programming model why can't we
另一个编程模型为什么我们不能
just be happy with what we already do
对我们已经做的事情感到满意
well one thing I've realized is we work
我意识到的一件事是我们工作
in a field where about every 10 years
在大约每十年的领域
will give a new name for what we already
将为我们已经存在的名称重新命名
do and get really get excited about it
并为此感到非常兴奋
so this time around things that get get
所以这次围绕着得到的东西
us excited are things like reactive
我们很兴奋是像反应性的东西
programming micro-services and things
对微服务和事物进行编程
like that well it turns out reactive
像那样好，原来是反应性的
programming is really not new it's been
编程真的不是新东西
around for a very long time in a way if
在很长一段时间内，如果
you really think about it it's kind of
你真的认为这有点
like it's what extreme programming did
就像极端编程所做的那样
well extreme programming didn't have
很好的极端编程没有
anything new and what was really new
任何新事物和真正的新事物
about extreme programming was there
关于极限编程
really it brought together certain
真的，它汇集了一定
practices we should really focus on in a
我们应该重点关注的实践
similar way the things that reactive
以类似方式反应的事物
programming bigs together has been
一起编程大人物已经
around for a while but what we have to
大约一会儿，但是我们必须
programming really does this brings the
编程确实确实带来了
emphasis for really why we should focus
强调为什么我们应该集中精力
on those four specific things it talks
关于它谈论的四个具体问题
about so it's really a rehashed
关于，所以真的很新
programming model that emphasizes on
强调的编程模型
scalability and response since
可扩展性和响应能力
positiveness but the question is why
积极性，但问题是为什么
should we really care about it and why
我们真的应该关心它吗，为什么
now well I'm almost nostalgic when I say
现在好了，我几乎怀旧了
this but I remember the days when I
这，但我记得我的日子
would wake up in the morning while the
会在早上醒来，而
coffee pod is brewing coffee my modem
咖啡荚正在煮咖啡，我的调制解调器
will connect and reconnect and I can
将连接并重新连接，我可以
hear that whoosh noise in my in the
听到在我的嗡嗡声
years and then of course I would call my
几年，然后我当然会打电话给我
friends and ask them what baud rate they
朋友问他们波特率是多少
are getting today well those days are
那些日子今天过得很好
long gone now we are dealing with
我们已经处理了很久了
devices that are constantly connected to
持续连接的设备
the Internet always connected every one
互联网总是连接每一个
of us carries around multiple different
我们每个人都携带着多种不同
devices with us every single day and as
每天与我们一起使用设备
a result we have applications that
结果我们有一些应用
constantly are working with data passing
一直在处理数据传递
data around well the second significant
第二个重要数据
thing that's happened is if you really
发生的事情是如果你真的
look back about 10 or 15 years ago
回首大约10或15年前
companies made a software available to
公司向
their employees and made their employees
他们的雇员，使他们的雇员
available to the interent public well
可供公众使用
those employees were using the system
这些员工正在使用该系统
are called captive users it doesn't
被称为俘虏用户，不是
matter what they think about on the
不管他们对
other hand we have applications being
另一方面，我们正在申请
available to real-world users now well
现在可以供现实世界的用户使用
it doesn't matter what the size of your
无论您的身材多大
company is I bet you have more customers
我敢打赌，您有更多客户
and users than number of employees so as
和用户数比员工数多
a result we have a lot greater demand on
结果，我们对
applications now then once we did years
现在我们做了几年的申请
ago and then of course we are also
以前当然我们也是
talking about various different devices
谈论各种不同的设备
constantly communicating well forget
不断沟通好忘了
about you know smart phones and watches
关于你的智能手机和手表
we're talking about earrings and nose
我们在谈论耳环和鼻子
rings and tongue rings all internet
环和舌头环所有互联网
enabled very soon what that really means
很快启用，这实际上意味着什么
is we are looking at devices that are
我们正在寻找的设备是
connected to us many constantly
不断地与我们联系
monitoring our health status imagine
监控我们的健康状况
your doctors can be notified about your
您的医生可以收到有关您的
health status even before you realize
健康状况，甚至在您意识到之前
and they can you know come down to help
他们可以知道下来帮助您
those days are not very far away so we
那些日子不是很遥远，所以我们
are talking about applications that are
谈论的是
constantly exchanging data we're also
不断交换数据，我们也
talking about high volume high frequency
谈论高频率
what we call as big data that that's
我们所谓的大数据就是
where we look today as well in a lot of
我们今天在很多地方
different applications so it's a it's a
不同的应用程序，所以它是一个
way to really structure and scale
真正构造和扩展的方式
applications this particular idea came
应用这个特殊的想法
from Microsoft Research Eric Meyer
来自Microsoft Research的Eric Meyer
created this idea of reactive
创造了反应性的想法
programming and it's been around for
编程，它已经为
quite a number of years before it gained
它获得了很多年
popularity in the field of Java and in
在Java领域和
JavaScript it's been around in the
JavaScript已经存在于
darknet area for a fairly long time but
暗网区域相当长的时间，但
but but main idea is the word reactive
但主要思想是“反应”一词
in this case simply refers to the
在这种情况下，仅指
ability of a system to respond to
系统响应的能力
stimuli and activities as they happen so
发生的刺激和活动
when it comes to these applications I
当涉及这些应用程序时，我
want you to step back and rethink about
希望您退后一步，重新思考
this just a little bit if you look back
如果回头看，这只是一点
at the past 20 years what have you been
在过去的20年中，您过得如何
doing for a good portion of that time
在那段时间里做了很多
well we can pretty much summarize that
好吧，我们可以总结一下
into one acronym which is crud so most
变成了一个首字母缩略词
of the applications we've been building
我们一直在构建的应用程序中
is crud applications we create data
是我们创建数据的原始应用程序
we've read data we update data and
我们已经读取了数据，我们更新了数据，
sometimes we delete data but at some
有时我们删除数据，但有时
point you wake up one morning and ask
点你早上醒来，问
the question is everything a crud
问题是一切都是粗俗的
application is it possible that maybe
应用程序是否有可能
you've just gone overboard
你刚刚落伍了
maybe we're just thinking about
也许我们只是在考虑
everything else crud maybe not
其他一切可能都不是
everything falls into
一切都陷入
this category well it turns out that is
这个类别很好，事实证明是
actually true that there's a lot of
实际上，有很多
applications that don't quite read data
不太读取数据的应用程序
process and set the data back like the
像这样处理并设置数据
way we think about it there is a wealthy
我们思考的方式有一个富裕的人
of applications that are interested in
对感兴趣的应用程序
processing data that might be flowing
处理可能正在流动的数据
through as time goes on and we want to
随着时间的流逝，我们希望
be able to respond to these activities
能够回应这些活动
these are intermediaries imagine you are
这些是中介，想象你是
interested in processing stock data as
有兴趣处理库存数据
the stock data comes through throughout
库存数据贯穿整个
the day the stock market is changing
股市变化的一天
you're not reading the stock data from a
您不是从
database per se all you're doing is you
数据库本身，您所要做的就是您
are responding to the stock data hey I
正在响应库存数据，嘿，我
want to purchase the stock price at this
想以此购买股票价格
particular time but but I want to wait
特定的时间，但我想等待
until this price really comes to that
直到这个价格真的到了
particular point and when it does I want
特定点以及何时需要
to really act on it I don't care about
真正采取行动，我不在乎
anything before I don't care about
我不在乎之前的任何事情
anything after that price is reached
达到这个价格后的任何东西
that could be an example or it could be
这可能是一个例子，也可能是
a device you're monitoring and when the
您正在监视的设备以及何时
device reaches a threshold you want to
设备达到您想要的阈值
respond to it it could be the fact that
对此作出回应可能是事实
you're listening to the weather
你在听天气
information and when the weather changes
信息以及天气变化的时间
certain pattern you want to respond to
您想要回应的特定模式
it so a lot of these things don't belong
所以很多这些东西不属于
to the correct model we have been
到我们一直使用的正确模型
talking about so we need to really
在谈论，所以我们需要真正
rethink about well this brings us to
重新思考好这将我们带到
four different concerns that are
四个不同的关注点是
extremely important and one of them is
极其重要，其中之一是
we should really think about how we
我们应该认真考虑一下
develop applications for these kinds of
开发此类应用程序
applications and one of them is to think
应用程序，其中之一就是思考
about message driven applications so we
关于消息驱动的应用程序，所以我们
want to be thinking about building
想考虑建设
applications where I'm going to go out
我要去的应用程序
and say that using a distributed
并说使用分布式
transaction on a centralized database is
集中式数据库上的事务是
so 20th century we should rethink about
所以20世纪我们应该重新考虑
how we bar model applications maybe
我们如何禁止模型应用程序
these disparate parts of the system
系统的这些不同部分
should be exchanging messages with each
应该与每个人交换消息
other rather than trying to use a
其他而不是尝试使用
centralized database or even distributed
集中式数据库甚至分布式
databases
资料库
well applications have to really think
应用程序必须真正思考
about elasticity I got a client I asked
关于弹性我有一个客户问
them how many users do you have on a
他们您有多少个用户
typical day and they said we got about
典型的一天，他们说我们到了
200 users on a typical day I kind of
在典型的一天有200位用户
laughed and said really 200 users you
笑着说真的有200位用户
guys are multi-billion dollar company
伙计们是数十亿美元的公司
you got 200 users and they said well you
您有200位用户，他们说的很好
asked us on a typical day how many
在典型的一天问我们多少
people we have and we have to end 200
我们拥有的人，我们必须结束200
people using but two and a half days in
人们在其中使用了两天半
a month about 50 million people use
一个月约有五千万人使用
their
其
so how do you scale for something like
所以你如何扩展像
that where hardly anyone uses your
几乎没有人使用您的
systems most of the time doing a little
系统大多数时候会做一点
admin stuff here and there and then
在这里和那里然后再管理东西
about two to two and a half days in a
大约两到两天半
month
月
50 million people jump on your system
5000万用户使用您的系统
and I'm going to say that trying to
我要说的是
maintain a local infrastructure and a
维护当地基础设施和
staff to maintain it is really
工作人员维护它真的
ridiculous in this time and age we
在这个时代和时代我们很荒谬
should really rethink about how we build
真的应该重新思考我们的建造方式
systems and this is what cloud computing
系统，这就是云计算
has really shown us we can be extremely
真的向我们展示了我们可以
elastic we can be time-based elastic or
弹性我们可以是基于时间的弹性
load based elastic when the demand goes
需求变化时基于负载的弹性
up you're going to make more revenue
你将获得更多收入
because of the demand you can bring in
因为你可以带来需求
more systems to support your demand and
更多系统可以满足您的需求
then when the demand diminishes you can
然后当需求减少时，您可以
have these systems go away well the
这些系统运转良好吗
cloud computing and elastic services
云计算和弹性服务
have shown this to us we can definitely
向我们展示了这一点，我们绝对可以
leverage that that's the other thing
利用那是另一回事
that reactive programming greatly
反应式编程
emphasizes the third thing it emphasizes
强调它强调的第三件事
is resilience resilience is so extremely
弹性弹性是如此之大
important look at your own smartphones
重要的是看看自己的智能手机
for a minute for me how many
一分钟对我来说
applications do you have on your smart
您的智能应用程序
phones I bet you have about hundreds of
我敢打赌你有几百个电话
applications on it how many do you use
上面的应用程序您使用了多少
on any given day you probably use a
在任何一天，您可能会使用
dozen applications what about the other
十几个应用程序又如何
applications well they're pure crap in
应用程序很好，它们纯属垃圾
fact you're so angry at them you have
其实你对他们很生气
left them there to die they don't
把他们留在那里死不死
deserve for you to touch them and even
值得您去触摸它们，甚至
delete it that's how we feel about
删除它就是我们的感受
applications that are performing not
表现不佳的应用程序
resilient at all so we should really
有弹性，所以我们应该真正
rethink about how we build applications
重新思考我们如何构建应用程序
resilience is extremely important
弹性非常重要
because if applications are not very
因为如果应用不是很
graceful in their failures we are not
在他们的失败中风度翩翩，我们不是
going to be very happy dealing with them
和他们打交道会很高兴
over time this reminds me of an
随着时间的流逝，这让我想起了
experience I was in a conference not too
我参加会议的经验不太好
long ago when a gentleman came to me and
很久以前，当一位绅士来找我
he said he was my student a few decades
他说他几十年来是我的学生
ago I've been teaching for about nearly
以前我已经教了差不多
close to thirty years now at the unity
团结已近三十年
of Houston and one of this he said I
休斯敦，其中之一他说我
took your class on distributed computing
上了分布式计算课
back in 1998 I said oh I remember that
我回想起1998年的时候
time when I was teaching that course he
我教那个课程的时候
said I want to tell you a story I said I
说我想告诉你一个故事我说我
love stories tell me a story he said
爱情故事告诉我一个他说的故事
while I was in your class and
我在你上课的时候
distributed object computing and we had
分布式对象计算，我们有了
a final semester demo and I was doing
最后一个学期的演示，我在做
the demo and right in the middle of the
演示，就在中间
demo you walked up quietly to my
演示，你安静地走到我的身边
computer disconnected the internet cable
电脑断开了互联网电缆
and then said continue and the project
然后说继续和项目
failed and I failed the course I said
不及格，我说的课程不及格
I'm really sorry to hear that you failed
听到您失败我真的很抱歉
my core
我的核心
is why would you want to share such a
这就是为什么你想分享这样一个
story with me he said well because
我跟他讲的故事很好，因为
there's a good news after this he went
他去之后有个好消息
on to say because that's the last day I
继续说，因为那是我的最后一天
ever did that mistake and you went on to
曾经犯过这个错误，然后你继续
say you see now when I program
说我编程的时候你现在看到
I don't just program the happy path I
我不只是编写幸福的道路
start with the things that could go
从可能发生的事情开始
wrong and I build resilience into the
错误的，我在其中建立了韧性
application and then he said well these
申请，然后他说好这些
days when I code I don't take this so
我编码的日子里我不这么认为
lightly in my office he said in front of
他在我办公室里轻轻地说
me on the cubicle I have a picture of
我在小隔间里有一张照片
Evel blanket in front of me and then I
在我面前铺上毯子，然后我
look at this picture every day when I
我每天看这张照片
code and I don't make this mistake I
代码，我不会犯这个错误
don't think we want to have pictures of
不要以为我们要
Evel venket in our desk or on the office
在我们的书桌上或办公室里的Even venket
but the point is we got a program for
但关键是我们有一个程序
resilience that's extremely important as
弹性非常重要，因为
well well then of course we want to also
那好吧，当然我们也要
think about responsiveness well we can
好好考虑一下响应能力
think of applications that are working
考虑正在运行的应用程序
but we are living in an age where of of
但是我们生活在一个
instant gratification we're not going to
即时满足，我们不会
just sit around and wait for
只是坐在那里等
applications to respond we want results
响应我们想要结果的应用程序
now when we want it fast
现在，当我们想要快速
well a good example of this would be to
一个很好的例子就是
think about you know infinite scroll for
想想你知道无限滚动
example well you scroll through this
很好的例子，您滚动浏览
application one morning which usually is
申请通常是一个早晨
slow it responded very quickly and
慢，它反应很快，
you're like wow that was pretty
你就像哇，真漂亮
instantaneous and then you realize at
瞬间，然后你意识到
the very end of this particular page you
此特定页面的结尾
scroll up and there is nothing and
向上滚动，没有任何内容，
before you could realize that if there's
在您意识到之前，如果有
nothing it fills up the next part of the
没有什么可以填满下一部分
data and that's an example of how
数据，这是如何
applications can take the time to work
应用程序可能会花费一些时间
while you are processing part of the
当您处理部分
response so it can be very responsive
响应，因此它可以非常响应
responsiveness is extremely important
响应能力非常重要
imagine you walk into a store and the
想象你走进一家商店，
store is pretty busy and you see the
商店很忙，您会看到
clerk who is busy with some customer
忙于一些客户的业务员
what do you normally do you probably
你通常会做什么
look around for a few minutes look at
看看周围几分钟
the ceiling look at the floor and you
天花板看着地板，你
walk away because there was no response
走开，因为没有回应
but on the other hand you make an you
但另一方面，你使你
walk into the store the clerk makes eye
店员走进商店
contact with you says I'll be with you
与你联系说我会和你在一起
shortly and goes back to help the
不久后回去帮助
customer who's already there
已经在那里的客户
you probably waited for a good 15 20
你可能在等一个好15 20
minutes why did you do that because you
分钟，为什么要这么做，因为你
felt you are important even though you
觉得你很重要，即使你
know you're not the point really is that
知道你不是重点是
that is the whole idea behind this is
这就是这个背后的全部想法是
when there is responsiveness we have a
当有响应时，我们有一个
loyalty of than the users and absolutely
比用户忠诚度和绝对
the applications that are not responses
不是响应的应用程序
are the ones that lose users very
是那些失去用户的人
quickly so these are the four
很快，所以这是四个
fundamental things that are essential in
基本要素
building applications we're going to use
建立我们将要使用的应用程序
message driven to communicate we're
信息驱动沟通我们
going to be using elastic services we go
我们将使用弹性服务
to program for resilience and be
进行韧性编程并成为
graceful about failure and of course
优雅地对待失败，当然
provide for responsive applications as
提供响应式应用程序作为
well so what is reactive programming
那么反应式编程是什么
well it is a programming model where we
好吧，这是一个编程模型
build applications using these these
使用这些构建应用程序
things to make the application really
使应用程序真正变的东西
resilient responsive but how do we go
应变能力强但我们该如何去
about doing this what can't we just
关于这样做，我们不能只是
build applications using multi-threading
使用多线程构建应用程序
well sure we can use multiple threads
很好，我们可以使用多个线程
but imagine what happens when you create
但是想象一下当您创建时会发生什么
threads that's the easy part then we got
线程是最简单的部分，然后我们得到了
to worry about race conditions about how
担心比赛条件如何
the threads communicate and so on that's
线程进行通信，依此类推
very very painful in general well and
总的来说非常非常痛苦
also if you really think about it when
如果您真的考虑过
you create threads there is no really
您创建线程没有真正
good way to communicate between thread
线程之间进行通讯的好方法
well we could use futures for doing this
好吧，我们可以用期货来做到这一点
well if you think about futures though
好吧，如果您考虑期货
what our futures do the futures
我们的期货做什么期货
basically are going to return there to
基本上要回到那里
you when the application computation is
您在应用程序计算时
over but you could go about and call a
结束，但您可以继续通话
future and the minute the future is in
未来以及未来的一刻
your hands what do you typically do you
你的手你通常做什么
turn around and call get and wait for
转身打电话给get等待
the response to be given to you
给你的回应
that's no future at all that's wasting
那根本没有未来，那是浪费
resources while you're waiting for the
等待中的资源
service and also it's really hard to
服务，而且真的很难
work with it oh wait a minute can't we
使用它哦，等等，我们不能
all be happy and use callbacks if you
所有人都应该开心，如果您使用回调，
think callbacks are a good idea I've got
认为回调是一个好主意
a suggestion for you just walk quietly
给你的建议就是安静地走
next to a JavaScript programmer and
在JavaScript程序员旁边
utter the word call back and watch them
说出“回拨”一词并观看他们
begin to cry uncontrollably because we
开始失控地哭泣，因为我们
have learned the call that don't work
学会了不起作用的电话
really well at all in fact the
实际上真的很好
JavaScript world has moved on to use
JavaScript世界已经开始使用
promises and other things and even
承诺等
reactive solutions for that matter so
反应性的解决方案，所以
what is it really that we are trying to
我们到底要做什么？
tackle what what are we getting to
解决我们要做什么
really well the first thing I want to
真的很好，我想做的第一件事
emphasize is maybe it's time to think
强调也许是时候思考了
beyond crud I'm not suggesting that we
毫无疑问，我不是在建议我们
wouldn't program in card anymore but not
不会再在卡中编程，但不会
everything we do probably has to be
我们所做的一切可能都必须
correct the second thing I would ask is
纠正我要问的第二件事是
what if we start thinking about data
如果我们开始考虑数据该怎么办
flow computing what if we start thinking
流计算，如果我们开始思考
about applications where we have a
关于我们拥有
source of data that made emit data and
发出数据的数据源
we are intermediaries that would receive
我们是会收到的中介
the data and as
数据和
you see the data we would perform our
您会看到我们将执行的数据
computations and in turn emit the data
计算，然后发出数据
moving forward to the next one in the
前进到下一个
series and we can have a series of
系列，我们可以有一系列
things that can respond to these
可以回应这些的事物
applications maybe data flow computing
应用程序也许是数据流计算
is a resurging once again this again is
再次复苏，这又是
a concept that's been around for a very
一个已经存在了很长时间的概念
long time but it's receiving special
时间长了，但是收到特别
attention right now but to understand
现在注意，但要了解
this let's take a slightly different
这让我们略有不同
example and and play with it so what I'm
例子，并玩弄它，所以我
going to do is to take a small problem
要做的是解决一个小问题
I'm going to look at a way to solve this
我将研究一种解决方法
problem and then see how we can go about
问题，然后看看我们该怎么做
you know rethinking about this problem
你知道对这个问题的重新思考
so for this I need a volunteer who has a
为此，我需要一个志愿者，
smartphone and who is interested in
智能手机，谁有兴趣
helping who wants to help me don't be
帮助谁想帮助我不要
shy
害羞
who wants to good sir what's your name
谁想要好先生，你叫什么名字
Leo you can be right there but you I
狮子座，你可以在那里，但你我
want you to give me information about
希望您给我有关的信息
three things I don't need your
我不需要你的三件事
smartphone I just need you with your
我只需要你的智能手机
smartphone so so here's the question for
智能手机，所以这是问题
you can you tell me the start price for
你可以告诉我的起拍价吗
these three things Google Amazon Intel
这三件事Google Amazon Intel
and Microsoft I want to stock prices for
和微软，我想以股票价格
these four things all right Leo we're
这四件事好吧，利奥，我们
waiting for you do you have the answer
等你，你有答案吗
for us leo uh almost he says he's not
对我们来说，狮子座，呃，他几乎说他不是
fast anybody thinks he's not fast enough
有人认为他不够快
for us all you have is just one price so
对我们来说，您所拥有的只是一个价格，所以
far yo this is disappointing
到目前为止，这令人失望
no he's too slow oh here guys look if
不，他太慢了哦，这里的家伙看看
somebody's helped as well
也有人帮忙
well thank you leo Thank You leo you
好，谢谢你，狮子座，谢谢你，狮子座
were wonderful
很棒
so you likely demonstrated how the
所以你可能展示了
worldwide weight works so what did he
世界范围的体重起作用，所以他做了什么
demonstrate there are several things
演示有几件事
Leah did not notice but you saw me and
利亚没注意到，但你看到了我，
Leo together there are several things
狮子座在一起有几件事
that happened here thanks for help well
发生在这里，谢谢您的帮助
first thing Leo did was we sent a
狮子座做的第一件事是我们发送了一封
request to him what did you do
向他要求你做了什么
immediately start on the job and he's
立即开始工作，他是
just nose-down at several point I said
我说过几下
this I don't care I don't want you to
这个我不在乎，我不要你
work on this anymore
不再为此工作
he did not notice this at all just like
他根本没有注意到这一点，就像
a web services a web service kind of
网络服务一种网络服务
goes nose down working on things and
垂头丧气地做事，
what happens when the rest service
休息服务时会发生什么
eventually donek says and the result
最终多奈克说，结果
there is like what did the user go these
就像用户去了这些
are gone for a long time ago right
很久以前就消失了
the second thing is you go to a site you
第二件事是你去一个网站
make a request the fight is taking too
要求也打架
long to respond what do you do you
渴望回应你你做什么
wanted to help so what do you do you do
想提供帮助，所以您会怎么做
a push button that sends two threads now
现在发送两个线程的按钮
working that's exactly what I did to Leo
这正是我对狮子座所做的
as well
以及
I kept nagging him more and now in
我不断kept他，现在
addition to looking at the answer he
除了看答案他
also had to keep responding to me this
也不得不继续回应我
is not going to help us at all but
根本不会帮助我们，但
that's the way we've been doing things
这就是我们做事的方式
for a very long time so you nicely
很长一段时间，所以你很好
demonstrated in fact he kind of branched
证明实际上他有点分支
off to something else along the way
一路上走到别的地方
which is pretty smart but this actually
这很聪明，但这实际上
happened in one of the sessions a few
发生在几个会议之一
months ago I was doing the same talk and
几个月前，我在做同样的演讲，
somebody like Leah wanted here but right
像利亚这样的人想要在这里但对
off the bat he hit something instantly
蝙蝠，他立刻击中了东西
what you did towards the end so when I
你到底做了什么，所以当我
gave him the four stop he says that
给了他四停，他说
gentleman said I'm not going to go look
先生说我不去看
up these prices immediately he recruited
他立即招募这些价格
four people around him he said you find
他周围有四个人，他说你找到了
the price for Microsoft you find the
您找到的Microsoft价格
price of Oriental you find the pressure
东方价格找到压力
Google and by doing so he demonstrated
谷歌，这样做他证明了
not only can a system suck you can waste
系统不仅会浪费您，还会浪费
a cluster of machines as well well the
一簇机器以及
point really is that it doesn't really
关键是它不是真的
have to be this way we got to really
必须是这样，我们必须真正
rethink about the way we do things so
重新思考我们做事的方式
how do we go about rethinking this and I
我们该如何重新考虑这一点，我
want to say efficiency is attained not
要说没有达到效率
by doing tasks faster but by avoiding
通过更快地完成任务，但避免
those tasks that shouldn't be done in
那些不应该在其中完成的任务
the first place
第一名
so the goal really is to not run faster
所以目标真的是不要跑得更快
and faster and faster but to rethink
越来越快，但需要重新思考
about how we actually do our work do our
关于我们实际上是如何工作的
tasks maybe there are tasks that we
任务也许有些任务，我们
shouldn't do does the user really care
用户真的应该在乎吗
about this can I postpone running this
关于这个我可以推迟运行
maybe until a later time and can I maybe
也许直到以后，我可能
do this minimally well I'm going to show
我要示范一下
you some examples but before that I want
你一些例子，但在此之前我要
to kind of connect this as I was
像我以前那样连接
learning about reactive programming
了解反应式编程
there's a void in front of me and I
我面前有空虚，我
don't understand where does the skull
不知道头骨在哪里
fit together and one of my realizations
放在一起，这是我的认识之一
was this is a really nice segue from
这是来自
functional programming because to me
函数式编程，因为对我而言
functional programming really is not
函数式编程真的不是
about immutability functional
关于不变性功能
programming is not about higher-order
编程与高阶无关
functions while those things are the
这些东西是
components ingredients are part of them
成分成分是其中的一部分
to programming for me the real essence
为我编程真正的本质
of functional programming really is
函数式编程的确是
function composition and lays
功能组成和位置
evaluations so
如此评价
if we can attain function composition
如果我们可以实现功能组合
and lazy evaluation well then we can
懒惰的评估好，那么我们可以
more effectively use the ideas of
更有效地利用
functional programming while social
社交函数式编程
programming kind of takes us all the way
编程方式带我们一路走
to the dorrance is here you go we got
到苦难在这里，你走了，我们得到了
laziness for you we got function
懒惰给你，我们有功能
composition and reactive programming
合成和反应式编程
takes you right from there and says well
带您从那里出发并说好
now that you can use function
现在您可以使用功能
composition and you can be lazy in your
组成，你可能会懒惰
evaluation let's leverage those ideas to
评估让我们利用这些想法来
move forward that's where these ideas
前进就是这些想法
come from so where this is taking us is
从那里来，这带我们去的是
our yes observable so what is observable
我们是可以观察到的，所以可以观察到的是
well it is the observable pattern but
好吧，这是可观察的模式，但是
with certain differences in it the first
首先有一定的区别
is you're going to be pulling the data
您将要提取数据吗
in the iterators whereas an observable
在迭代器中，而可观察的
the data gets pushed towards you it
数据被推向您
could be synchronous or asynchronous
可以是同步的或异步的
well a lot of times pushing synchrony
很多时候推动同步
are asynchronous too early in the game
在游戏中太早了
makes the application extremely complex
使应用程序极其复杂
and hard to work with well the beauty in
并努力与美丽的人一起工作
this area is it can postpone you can't
这个区域可以推迟吗？
postpone those until a later time so the
将那些推迟到以后
observer really has a couple of
观察者确实有几个
different interesting things to make
做出不同有趣的事情
this happen for us well the very first
这首先发生在我们身上
thing about observable is that it's got
可观察的是
a data set channel and a bear channel is
数据集通道和熊通道是
through which the data keeps strength by
通过这些数据可以保持实力
emitting or transmitting towards you but
向您发射或传播，但
what what do we do when things go wrong
出现问题时我们该怎么办
well then things go wrong you want to
好吧，你想做的事情出了问题
handle the errors but the worst thing
处理错误，但最糟糕的事情
about errors is we call them exception
关于错误，我们称它们为异常
maybe you should have called them normal
也许您应该称他们为正常
because they can happen at any time
因为它们可以随时发生
so rather than throwing exceptions at
所以不要在抛出异常
you observables have a separate channel
你观察者有一个单独的渠道
for the errors themselves sick wait
对于错误本身生病的等待
there is a data channel and there's a
有一个数据通道，有一个
error channel well the data channel has
错误通道数据通道具有
the data the error channel has the error
错误通道中的数据有错误
and of course anytime there's an error
当然任何时候都有错误
to the error channel there will be no
到错误通道不会有
more data coming through their channel
他们的渠道有更多数据
and and that's a way for you to know
这是让你知道的方式
that there's an error and of course when
这是有错误的，当然
you respond to the error you're not
您对错误的回应不是
going to be pushed more data towards you
将会向您推送更多数据
kind of like the circuit breaker model
有点像断路器模型
and of course I mentioned there could be
我当然提到过
synchronous or asynchronous let's take a
同步或异步让我们来
look at how these things can evolve with
看看这些东西如何演变
a quick little example here so what I
这里有个简单的小例子
want to do here is I've got symbols as a
想在这里做的是我有符号作为
collection here so I'm
在这里收藏所以我
to say stock server I'll go and say get
说股票服务器，我去说得到
feed over here and I'll pass the symbols
在这里喂食，我将传递符号
given to us to the get feed method
给我们的get feed方法
well the get feed is going to of course
好吧，获取提要当然
give us the data as it's going to happen
向我们提供即将发生的数据
but we got to implement it somehow well
但是我们必须以某种方式很好地实施它
it turns out there are several
原来有几个
implementations available for doing
可用的实现
reactive programming on Java there's not
Java上的反应式编程没有
one solution you could use any of those
一种解决方案，您可以使用其中任何一种
different solutions I'm going to just
我将要介绍的不同解决方案
use one of them which is rx Java which
使用其中之一是rx Java
is implemented by Netflix apparently
是由Netflix实施的
they had some screaming problems to deal
他们有一些尖叫的问题要解决
with so they decided to open-source
因此，他们决定开源
their solution but the ideas are pretty
他们的解决方案，但想法很漂亮
much the same the aps are slightly
几乎一样的APS略有
different here and there but you could
在这里和那里不同，但你可以
go away and use this in some other
走开，在其他一些地方使用
library if you wanted to but the ideas
图书馆，如果你想但是想法
observables really is pretty dominant in
可观察的东西在
this and I'm going to say observable of
这个，我要说的是
stock info is what I really want to use
股票信息是我真正想要使用的
here so I start with an observable and
在这里，我从一个可观察的
that observable as you can see is coming
如您所见，可以观察到
from the i/o dot reactive X start
从I / O点反应式X开始
observable so how do I go about creating
可观察的，那么我该如何去创造
an observable how do I use it we'll come
可以观察到的我将如何使用
back to that part in just a few minutes
只需几分钟即可回到该部分
so we'll move on to this side over here
所以我们将移到这边
well now that I have an observable on my
好吧，现在我有一个可观察的
hand I'm going to say that's the feed
我要说的就是饲料
and then of course I'll go ahead and say
然后我当然会说
got observable and I have an observable
可以观察到，我也可以观察到
at my hand but I want to go ahead and do
在我的手边，但我想继续做
something with the observable have not
可观察的东西没有
done that yet we'll come back to that in
做到了这一点，我们将回到
just a minute going back over here I'm
等一下我回到这里
going to say observable dark create and
会说可观察到的黑暗创造和
this uses the idea that we don't want is
这使用了我们不想要的想法
a constructor but we will use a factory
构造函数，但我们将使用工厂
method to create an object so we are
创建对象的方法
seeing observable are create to create
眼见为实创造
the object so in this case I'm going to
该对象，所以在这种情况下，我要
get a subscriber to be given to me and
得到一个订户给我，
I'm going to go ahead and emit into the
我要继续往前走
subscriber some data as it as it so
订阅者原样保留一些数据
happens so we need an emit method for us
发生了，所以我们需要一个发射方法
to be able to use this now so the
能够现在使用它，所以
observable is created the observable
可观察的被创造可观察的
gives you a reference and observable is
给你一个参考，可观察的是
nothing but our data stream oh wait a
只是我们的数据流哦，等等
minute let's quickly talk about what is
分钟，让我们快速谈谈什么是
the difference between observable and
可观察与
stream as we know streams in Java 8 well
我们知道的Java 8流
there are a couple of very key clear
有几个非常关键的明确
differences in them well they both
他们俩之间的差异很好
streams in Java 8 and
Java 8和
observable our data emitters so they
可以观察到我们的数据发射器
both are going to emit data towards you
两者都会向您发射数据
but the stream API in Java aid do not
但是Java帮助中的流API却没有
deal with exceptions at all on the God
处理上帝所有的例外
on the other hand observables have a
另一方面，可观察对象有一个
clearly separate data channel and error
明确区分数据通道和错误
channel for one so they have a better
渠道，让他们有更好的
handle on the exceptions or errors for
处理异常或错误
you and the second thing of course is
你和第二件事当然是
that the they both are lazy of course so
他们俩当然很懒
they could be sending data at any time
他们可以随时发送数据
they will be pushing data towards you
他们会向您推送数据
but the way they handle data is one of
但是他们处理数据的方式之一是
those differences if you will in how
这些差异，如果你会如何
they handle would with things so in this
他们会处理这样的事情
case I'm going to create a emit method
情况下，我要创建一个发射方法
and then the emmett method I'm going to
然后我要使用的emmett方法
go ahead and say this is going to be
继续说这将是
receiving a subscriber and it's going to
接收订户，这将
emit the data so I'm going to say start
发出数据，所以我要说开始
emitting over here so we can actually
散布在这里，所以我们实际上可以
see that particular method call as well
也可以看到特定的方法调用
but right off the bat let's go ahead and
但是马上就开始吧，
run this and see what it's going to do
运行这个，看看它会做什么
and you can see that it said god
你会看到它说上帝
observable but it didn't do anything
可以观察到，但是它什么也没做
more just to emphasize the fact that it
只是为了强调事实，
is absolutely lazy so it's not going to
绝对是懒惰，所以它不会
do any work until you really demand a
做任何工作，直到您真正需要
connection to it and say I am really
连接到它，说我真的
ready to process your data it doesn't
准备处理您的数据
really start emitting any data is that
真正开始发出任何数据的是
lazy well now that we are receiving here
现在我们在这里懒惰好了
why don't we go ahead and do something
为什么我们不继续做某事
with the data so I'm going to go to the
与数据，所以我要去
feed and say subscribe and now I can say
喂并说订阅，现在我可以说
outpoured so in this case I'll simply
倾盆大雨，所以在这种情况下，我会简单地
say system dot out print line and I'll
说系统点出打印行，我会
just print the data in this case so that
在这种情况下只需打印数据即可
we can see the data being transmitted
我们可以看到正在传输的数据
towards as well of course in this case
当然在这种情况下
I'm not still emitting any data so when
我仍然没有发出任何数据，所以当
I go ahead and run this code though you
我继续运行此代码，尽管你
can see it said God observable it said
可以看到它说上帝可以观察到它说
start emitting data but the start
开始发射数据，但开始
emitting data really happened because we
发出数据确实发生了，因为我们
truly subscribed to the data
真正订阅数据
well now what I'm going to do here is to
现在我要在这里做的是
go back to this emitter and I'm going to
回到这个发射器，我要
say at this point why don't we say
说到这一点，为什么我们不说
awhile true in this case and then I'm
在这种情况下是一会儿，然后我
going to say well we got the subscriber
说得好，我们得到了订户
on our hand but I also like to have the
在我们手上，但我也喜欢
symbol given to me as well because that
也给我符号，因为
would be after all pretty useful to have
毕竟有非常有用
so in this case I'm going to pass the
所以在这种情况下，我将通过
symbol to this as let's say the second
像第二个这样的符号
parameter so now I can say
参数，所以我现在可以说
in here well now they have the symbols
现在在这里，他们有了符号
at my hand I'll say symbols doc and then
在我手上，我会说符号doc，然后
I will go ahead and say stream I'll use
我会继续说我将使用流
the Java eight stream this is purely an
Java 8流，这纯粹是
implementation detail at this point then
那么此时的实现细节
I'm going to say math and I'll say stock
我要说数学，我要说股票
info and I'll call a fetch method well
信息，我会很好地调用fetch方法
the fetch method of stock info is going
股票信息的获取方法正在发展
to go out and get the stock price parse
出去获取股票价格解析
the data and give it back to as a stock
数据并将其作为库存返还
info and then once I have the data I'm
信息，然后一旦我有了数据，我就
going to say for each and in this case
在这种情况下，每个人都会说
if you give me a stock info I'm going to
如果您给我股票信息，我将
say subscriber dot on next and send the
在下一步说订户点并发送
stock info to that particular oops wrong
股票信息到特定的哎呀错误
one and in that case I'll say stock info
一个，在那种情况下，我会说股票信息
and then I'm going to say stock a stock
然后我要说股票
info and I will just go ahead and send
信息，我将继续发送
the stock info to this object at this
此对象的库存信息
particular point well in this case of
在这种情况下很好的一点
course the map is going to return a
当然，地图将返回一个
stock info we could receive the stock
库存信息，我们可以接收库存
info and pass it on to the subscriber at
信息并将其传递给订户
this point or we could just simply use
这一点或者我们可以简单地使用
the Java eight syntax and say well we
Java八种语法，说得好，我们
could simply use a double colon on this
可以在此简单地使用双冒号
but the whole point is here in respect
但重点在于
to the syntax you can think of this as a
的语法，你可以认为这是一个
mouth of the data channel where you
您所在的数据通道口
start emitting the data through the data
开始通过数据发射数据
channel of the observable and of course
可观察的通道，当然
now that you're emitting the data from
现在您正在从
here the data should be arriving on this
在这里数据应该到达此
other side args Java itself does things
Java本身执行其他操作
within one particular JVM but if you
在一个特定的JVM中，但是如果您
really want to go across the jaebeum's
真的很想去看一下红豆的
there are other solutions again one
还有其他解决方案之一
example of this is vertex vertex
顶点就是这个例子
actually uses rx Java API but wraps and
实际使用rx Java API但包装和
gives you the ability to go across
使您能够穿越
machines as well so you could use one of
机器，所以您可以使用其中之一
these different solutions to deal with
这些不同的解决方案
so as you can see this is getting the
如您所见，这正在
data and Google is pretty close to what
数据，Google几乎与
Leo pointed us to us so thanks Leo gain
狮子座把我们指给我们，谢谢狮子座
but you can see that the data is
但您可以看到数据是
arriving at this point but this is just
到了这一点，但这仅仅是
transmitting the data for us and we are
为我们传输数据，我们正在
receiving the data so but what is the
接收数据，所以什么是
where does this lead us to well there's
这会导致我们走向何方
the synchronous solution we are
我们是同步解决方案
transmitting data but where we really
传输数据，但我们真正在哪里
want to go from here is an ability to
想从这里走是一种能力
interact with the systems and
与系统互动并
communicate across these different
跨这些不同的沟通
endpoints so in here imagine you have an
端点，所以在这里想象你有一个
observable sending data to words you
可观察到的发送数据到你的单词
but there are times when we should be
但是有时候我们应该
very mindful of resources the observable
非常注意可观察的资源
the source is using resources to talk to
来源正在使用资源与之交谈
you and you are using resources to
您和您正在使用资源来
receive the data as well and if what if
以及接收数据，如果
there is no more data coming towards you
没有更多数据向您发送
it would be nice to be told that there
有人告诉我那里很高兴
is no more data coming towards you well
没有更多的数据向您迈进
this is where I said there are two
这是我说的两个
channels well I kind of lied to you
渠道很好，我对你撒谎
there are three channels there's a data
有三个频道有一个数据
channel to which there will be data
数据通道
coming through does the error channel
通过错误通道
through which an error may come through
通过它可能会发生错误
and there's a complete channel through
并且有一个完整的渠道
which a signal for complete comes
哪个信号完成
through well the way the observables
通过观察者的方式
work typically is there might be a zero
通常工作可能是零
or more data coming through the data
或来自数据的更多数据
channel so imagine there's there data
频道，所以想像那里有数据
coming through the data channel and at
通过数据通道到达
any time it's going to tell you there is
任何时候它会告诉你
no more data well it's going to send a
没有更多的数据，它将发送一个
complete signal and the minute it sends
完成信号及其发送的分钟
a complete signal the data channel
完整的信号数据通道
closes up and there will be no more data
关闭，将没有更多数据
coming through the data channel well
顺利通过数据通道
just to illustrate this point let me go
只是为了说明这一点，让我走
back here to this code and say in this
回到这里这段代码，并在此说
case let's say count is less than let's
假设计数少于我们
say three and I'll go ahead and start a
说三个，然后我就开始
count is equal to zero and in this case
计数等于零，在这种情况下
let's go ahead and increment this count
让我们继续增加这个数量
for our purpose and then in the very end
为了我们的目的，然后到最后
I'm going to say go ahead and say
我要说继续说
subscriber on next and then send a new
下一个订阅者，然后发送新
stock info let's go ahead and say info
股票信息让我们继续说信息
of dummy and then a zero point zero as a
的虚拟，然后零点零作为
price just to you know illustrate the
价格只是你知道的说明
point about the way these channels
指出这些渠道的方式
actually work so when I run this code
实际工作，所以当我运行此代码
you can see the data is being emitted at
您可以看到正在发送数据
this point and the data is going to be
至此，数据将是
pulled from the service it looks like
从服务看起来像拉
maybe when a connection is a bit slow
也许当连接有点慢
here so it's not respond oh there you go
在这里，所以它没有回应哦，你去
so it starts moving okay it's terribly
所以它开始运动好极了
slow alright so now we can see
好慢，现在我们可以看到
eventually it's a dummy zero point zero
最终是一个虚拟零点零
but on the other hand I'm going to go
但另一方面，我要去
back here and at the very end of this
回到这里，在这末尾
I'm going to go ahead and say subscriber
我要继续说订户
dot on complete and I'm going to send a
点完成后，我将发送一个
complete signal well on the receiving
接收时信号完整
end I'm going to go ahead and add one
结束，我要继续添加一个
more thing for now I'll just say system
现在我还要说系统
dot out print line will it worry about
点出打印线会担心吗
what this is in a few minutes but I'm
几分钟后这是什么，但我
going to say I'm receiving no data but
会说我什么也没收到
I'm going to simply output done over
我将简单地完成输出
here as the very very last one well if
这是最后一口井，如果
you look at these things these
你看这些东西
three lines are really the three
三行真的是三行
different things that we are talking
我们正在谈论的不同的事情
about the first line is your data
关于第一行是您的数据
channel the second line is your error
引导第二行是您的错误
Channel and the third line is your
频道和第三行是您的
complete channel so there's a way for
完整的频道，所以有一种方法
you to receive data one of these three
您将接收以下三个数据之一
channels for you so you can either be
为您提供渠道，因此您可以
receiving data to the data channel edit
接收数据到数据通道编辑
through the error channel are the
通过错误通道
complete signal to the complete channel
完整信号到完整通道
but in the sense though notice that I
但在某种意义上，尽管注意我
put a dummy out in the very end after
在最后把一个假人放出来
complete but remember that once they're
完成，但请记住，一旦他们
complete signal comes the data channel
完整的信号来自数据通道
close up so that's why in this output
关闭，这就是为什么在此输出中
you note as it says done but it never
你注意到它说完成了，但是从来没有
received the dummy out as the output
收到虚拟输出
that's because the minute complete
那是因为分钟完成了
signal was sent that data channel closes
发送了数据通道关闭的信号
up and this becomes purely and no up
上升，这变得纯粹，没有上升
it's never going to leave the observable
它永远不会离开可观察的
and go to the client and of course the
去客户那里，当然
observer or the client or the subscriber
观察者或客户或订户
can do a clean-up operation right there
可以在那里进行清理操作
this gives you an idea how you can send
这使您知道如何发送
a signal from the subscriber to the
从订户到
observable to the observer and say that
观察者可以观察到并说
I'm done but what about the other way
我做完了，但是反过来呢
around there are times when you want to
周围有时候你想
unsubscribe as well so for example if I
也取消订阅，例如，如果我
go ahead and say give me all the stock
继续说给我所有的股票
symbols and the prices and the observe
符号和价格及观察
will start transmitting the data to me
将开始向我传输数据
but at some point I realize the price of
但在某个时候我意识到
the stock is my favorable price I want
股票是我想要的最优惠的价格
to perform a trade I no longer want to
进行交易，我不再想要
get the data from the server well I
我很好地从服务器获取数据
could send an unsubscribe and say thanks
可以发送退订并说谢谢
but no thanks don't send me any more
但不用了，谢谢，不要再寄给我
data so this gives an opportunity for
数据，因此为
you to unsubscribe from the source and
您取消订阅源，并且
say don't bother sending this to me
说不要打扰发送给我
anymore so in this case what you can do
再这样，在这种情况下，您可以做什么
is you can throw in an unsubscribe as
您可以取消订阅吗
well well we can do a little bit more
好吧，我们可以做更多的事情
work for that so what we could do in
为此工作，我们可以在
this case is we could go ahead and build
这种情况下，我们可以继续构建
up a new and we could say observe we'll
新的，我们可以说观察我们会
call this as my observable so I could
称其为我可观察的，所以我可以
create my own observable right here
在这里创建我自己的可观察的
observer rather so I can create my own
观察者而不是我可以创建自己的观察者
observer and in this of course I have my
观察者，当然我有我的
observer and this observer can of course
观察者，这个观察者当然可以
implement a certain methods that are
实现某些方法
required for starting to observe
开始观察所需
so we could implement a bunch of methods
所以我们可以实现一堆方法
on this on this observer
在这个观察者身上
well this observer of course is going to
这个观察者当然会
support the interface that this
支持这个的界面
subscribers expecting which is the
订户期望哪个
observer so we could go ahead and create
观察者，所以我们可以继续创造
a little class here so we could say for
这里有一小堂课，所以我们可以说
example new observable well observer
新的可观察井观察者示例
rather and then we could say I want to
相反，然后我们可以说我想
implement the methods that this guy is
实现这个家伙的方法
going to expect so let's redo this right
期待如此，让我们重做这个权利
here so we can say feed art subscribe
在这里，所以我们可以说订阅艺术订阅
and you will call it as observer and
您将其称为观察者，
then this is going to be the stock info
那么这将是股票信息
of the observer that we would like to go
我们想去的观察者
ahead and implement it well in this case
提前在这种情况下很好地实施
of course we're going to implement these
当然我们要实现这些
these methods so what are the methods
这些方法是什么
I'm going to implement for for this
我将为此实现
purpose well I'm going to implement the
目的很好，我要实施
method which is the on next we saw that
接下来我们看到的是
earlier so this is going to be simply
较早，所以这将很简单
the stock info that I want to respond
我要回复的库存信息
with so this is going to be a part of me
所以这将成为我的一部分
I made a mistake here this should be
我在这里犯了一个错误
info rather so that's a stock info
信息，所以这是一个股票信息
that's the observer going to get back to
那是观察者要回到的
us so we can simply say I'm going to
我们，所以我们可以简单地说我要
receive the stock info and this case of
接收库存信息，这种情况下
course I'm going to say print out the
当然我要说打印出来
stock info so I'll just print the stock
库存信息，所以我只打印库存
info given to me I can also print the
给我的信息我也可以打印
complete signal right here ignore the
完整的信号就在这里，忽略
error for now and then of course I can
暂时的错误，当然我可以
say done right now but I can also do one
说现在完成，但我也可以做一个
more thing for example let's say on the
比方说更多
next I could say if the stock info dot
接下来我可以说股票信息点
value is let's say less than oh let's
值比不说哦
say about $40 we could immediately say
说40美元，我们可以立即说
output a you know unsubscribing so we
输出您知道取消订阅的信息，因此我们
could say unsubscribing and we could
可以说退订，我们可以
then send a request to unsubscribe well
然后发送要求退订的请求
how in the world can we do this well we
我们如何才能做到这一点，我们
could say in this case we are receiving
可以说在这种情况下，我们正在收到
a disposable so I will go ahead and
一次性的，所以我会继续
store that away here as disposable and
存放在这里作为一次性和
we will store that into a variable so
我们将其存储到变量中
disposable equals the given disposable
一次性等于给定的一次性
and then we can nicely go back here and
然后我们可以很好地回到这里
say the disposable dart and then we
说一次性飞镖，然后我们
could dispose off and say don't bother
可以处理掉，说不要打扰
sending me any more data so we can see
向我发送更多数据，以便我们可以看到
the transmission of the data starts up
数据传输开始
depending on how the internet is going
取决于互联网的运行状况
to send the data well as the data
很好地发送数据
arrives the middle bit
到达中间位
less than a 40 we can unsubscribe right
少于40，我们可以取消订阅
away and we're not going to get any more
走了，我们不会再得到任何东西
data moving forward that is an example
数据向前发展就是一个例子
of how we can go ahead and unsubscribe
我们如何继续和退订
from the calls at any given time so the
从任何给定时间的通话中
observers can say don't bother sending
观察者可以说不要打扰
any more data to me and that way they
任何更多的数据给我，他们
can be very mindful of resources the
可以非常注意资源
server is going to use as well well that
服务器也将很好地使用
gives us an idea about how we can
让我们知道如何
process it but the big elephant in the
处理它，但是
room of course is how do you handle the
房间当然是您如何处理
errors
错误
well errors are something extremely
错误是极端的东西
important to deal with properly so in
重要的是要妥善处理
other words what happens when things do
换句话说，当事情发生时会发生什么
go wrong well when things go wrong
出问题时会做好事
imagine you're on a multi-threaded
想象你在多线程上
application and in a multi-threaded
应用程序并在多线程中
application when things do go wrong you
出现问题时的应用程序
want to be able to know a what went
希望能够知道发生了什么
wrong and you want to be able to handle
错误，您希望能够处理
that well when you have thousand threads
当你有上千个线程的时候
and if several threads begin to fail
如果多个线程开始失败
there's no real good way to communicate
没有真正好的交流方式
all the information a multi-threaded
所有信息都是多线程的
situation it becomes really hard to work
情况变得很难工作
with it what we're going to do here
有了它，我们在这里要做的
instead is exception handling is
相反，异常处理是
something we have really struggled with
我们真正挣扎的东西
throughout ignore the history of
始终无视历史
computing well what did we do a long
计算良好，我们做了很长时间
time ago we said we're going to return a
前段时间，我们说我们要返回一个
result if the result is positive it's a
如果结果为正，则为
good data if the result is negative it's
好的数据，如果结果为负，则为
an error then we realize gosh that
一个错误，然后我们意识到天哪
doesn't make sense because the data
没有意义，因为数据
could be negative - and then we try
可能为负-然后我们尝试
something else this was the days of the
这是其他的日子
80s we returned an error all the time if
80年代，如果
it is zero it's good if it's not zero
它为零，如果不为零，则很好
it's an error yeah that's awesome
这是一个错误，很棒
but wait a minute worse the data oh you
但是请稍等一下数据哦
will send an extra parameter to the
将发送一个额外的参数给
function the function will fill the
函数该函数将填充
parameter with the data and return to
参数与数据并返回
you that made things very clumsy for us
你让我们变得很笨拙
to use and one of the errors you had to
使用和您必须要犯的错误之一
deal with was that the function forgot
处理的是功能忘记了
to fill the data in the first place our
首先填充数据
Houston forgot to send the proper holder
休斯敦忘记发送适当的持有人
for it okay that didn't go really well
因为那还不错，进展并不顺利
then what did we do we said we're going
然后我们做了什么，我们说我们要去
to do exception handling exception
做异常处理
handling was wonderful wasn't it because
处理很棒是不是因为
a function could throw exception and you
函数可能会引发异常，而您
could simply ignore it with an empty
可以简单地忽略它
cache block that was frustrating I can
可以让我沮丧的缓存块
tell you a week doesn't go by when I
告诉你一个星期不走，当我
plead with the programmer
向程序员恳求
please no empty hat blocks back didn't
请没有空帽子阻止没有
go very well at all and there's another
一切都很好，还有另一个
thing when something goes wrong what
当事情出了问题的时候
happens it throws an exception at you
碰巧会向您抛出异常
how civil is that how would you feel
你感觉如何文明
when people throw things at you
当人们向你扔东西
well the after programming is extremely
好了，后期编程非常
civil it doesn't throw anything at you
民间的，对你没有任何影响
it hands you the error and says here you
它会给您错误并在这里说您
go and shakes your hand and says we'll
去握手吧，说我们会
be civil about this that's one of the
对此保持谦虚是其中之一
really nice things about it it takes the
真的很不错的事情
exceptions but it gives you the
例外，但它给你
exceptions through the error channel
通过错误通道的异常
very nicely let's see how that works
非常高兴让我们看看它是如何工作的
actually in this example so I'm going to
实际上在这个例子中，所以我要
go ahead and say system dot out and
继续说系统熄灭，
let's say print one well we know that
假设我们打印一个，我们知道
this is going to be the data channel
这将是数据通道
coming through but I'm going to say
来，但我要说
given an error I'll go ahead an output
给定一个错误，我将继续输出
error right here in uppercase and then I
错误在这里大写，然后我
will say plus over here and then I will
会在这里说加号，然后我会
just print the error and then finally
只是打印错误，然后最后
here comes the data we'll say output
这就是我们要说的输出数据
done to say that we're going to receive
只是说我们将要收到
the output as the complete signal well
输出作为完整的信号
when I run this code in this case of
当我在这种情况下运行此代码时
course you can see that things are going
当然你可以看到事情正在发展
well and you are getting the data and
好吧，您正在获取数据，
eventually you're done but on the other
最终你完成了，但另一方面
hand let's say in this case I'm going to
假设我们在这种情况下
go ahead and increase this to let's say
继续增加这个，可以说
300 for a minute but I'm going to go to
300分钟，但我要去
my stock info and in the stock info at a
我的股票信息以及在股票信息中的
random time I'm going to blow up with
我要炸毁的随机时间
the old oops ran into trouble but notice
老家伙遇到了麻烦，但请注意
this is going to throw an exception but
这将引发异常，但是
this guy is not dealing with exceptions
这个家伙没有处理异常
however the reactive system say is oh
但是反应系统说是哦
wait a minute you are transmitting
等一下你传送
emitting data and while you're the
发射数据，而当你
source of the data emission something
数据发射的来源
went wrong and things blew up we're not
出了错，事情发生了，我们不是
going to just simply you know throw
只是简单地你知道扔
we're going to capture that exception
我们将捕获该异常
and send it as a as an error in other
并作为错误发送给其他人
words errors are first-class citizens as
错误是一等公民
well you're not treating errors at
好吧，您不是在处理错误
something secondary you are treating
您正在治疗的次要事物
them with as much respect they deserve
他们应该得到应有的尊重
as the data deserves and that is one of
数据应得的，这是其中之一
the nice things about it so when I run
不错的事情，所以当我跑步
this program this time though notice it
这次虽然注意这个程序
starts emitting the data but notice when
开始发射数据，但请注意何时
things did go wrong when it blew up
炸毁时确实出错了
randomly that exception was
那个例外是
grabbed and notice the word ever in
抓住并注意到这个词
front of the message that error came
错误出现的消息的前面
right from there whereas the exception I
从那里开始，而我例外
threw really had boobs ran into trouble
真的把胸部碰到麻烦了
and that shows how that exception over
这说明了该异常是如何结束的
there was grabbed
有被抓住
but politely given to you through the
但有礼貌地通过
error channel in a way that you can
错误通道，您可以
actually handle furthermore when the
实际上，当
error does come out the data channel
错误确实从数据通道中出来
closes up there will be no more data
关闭将没有更多数据
coming to the data channel and you can
进入数据通道，您可以
handle and deal with the error properly
正确处理和处理错误
on your side so that shows how we can
在你身边，这表明我们如何
handle errors as well
也可以处理错误
very nicely well I want to just touch on
很好，我想谈谈
just a few remaining things in the time
剩下的时间只是几件事
we have that we need to really think
我们有需要真正思考
about as other considerations I showed
和我展示的其他注意事项一样
you a fairly simple example here of an
你是一个相当简单的例子
observable and an observer where the
可观察到的观察者
observable image data and the observer
可观察的图像数据和观察者
is is is using the data being
是正在使用数据
transmitted but there are typically a
传输，但通常有一个
lot of different things we would
我们会做很多不同的事情
normally want to do let's go ahead and
通常想做，让我们继续前进，
remove this error for now and then we'll
暂时删除此错误，然后我们将
continue further now in this case of
在这种情况下，请继续
course if I run the program that's going
当然，如果我运行要运行的程序
to start transferring data for quite a
开始传输数据
while as you can see in here but there
正如你在这里看到的那样
are things you can actually do quite
是您实际上可以做的事情
effectively along the way for example
例如有效地进行
notice the prices are ranging from $800
注意价格从$ 800不等
on one side to you know all the way down
一方面，你一直知道
to $35 and so on but let's say that I'm
到$ 35等，但假设我是
actually interested in only certain
实际上只对某些感兴趣
values that I'm interested in observing
我有兴趣观察的价值观
well what I can do in that case is I can
那我可以做的就是
nicely use this approach to build up on
很好地使用这种方法来建立
these things very nicely so for example
这些东西很好，例如
if you go back to this code I'm going to
如果您返回此代码，我将
remove these messages for just a minute
删除这些消息仅一分钟
so we can just see the data coming
这样我们就可以看到数据
through you can see that in this case
通过这种情况，您可以看到
once I turn it on we're going to have
一旦我打开它，我们将拥有
the data coming through and it displays
数据通过并显示
all these data I'll stop this for now
所有这些数据，我暂时将其停止
but what I can do is I can say well I
但我能做的就是说好我
don't want to see all the data you know
不想看到您知道的所有数据
imagine for a minute that you are
想象一下你是
dealing with a situation where you are
处理你所在的情况
looking at the device the device is
看着设备
transmitting data and you are not
传输数据而您不是
interested in all the data well let's
对所有数据都感兴趣，让我们
say for a minute
说一分钟
I'm I'm an observable and I'm emitting
我是一个可观察的人，我在散发
data constantly and let's say Leo here
不断的数据，在这里说狮子座
is an observer he is interested
是他感兴趣的观察者
receiving some data I'm sending but a
收到我发送的一些数据，但是
little bit later he says you know what
过了一会儿他说你知道
hate this is great but I don't want
讨厌这很棒，但我不想
everything that you are emitting I only
你散发的一切，我只
want certain things that you are sending
想要发送某些东西
and not other things well unfortunately
不幸的是没有其他事情
I don't want to deal with Leo's requests
我不想处理狮子座的要求
well not that I don't care about him but
好吧，不是我不在乎他，而是
we'll use a technical term for it
我们将使用一个技术术语
it's called cohesion and single
这被称为凝聚力和单身
responsibility principle right well I'm
我很好的责任原则
going to do what I'm going to do I don't
要去做我要去做的事
want to start customizing what I do for
想开始自定义我的工作
just one of my observers but because
只是我的一位观察者，但是因为
somebody else may really care about
可能有人真的在乎
everything I send so what do we do
我发送的所有邮件，我们该怎么办
what's going to have an intermediary
会有什么中介
right now this intermediary says dory
现在，这个中介说多莉
about it I'm going to sit between Leo
关于这个，我要坐在狮子座之间
and and this observable venket and it
还有这个可观察的venket
says I'm going to start filtering out
说我要开始过滤掉
things that Leo doesn't care about
狮子座不关心的事情
there's a very powerful model as you can
有一个非常强大的模型
see notice we have the feed up there but
看到通知，我们在那里有提要，但是
the feed actually is right this one
饲料实际上是正确的
returned by the get feed method but
由get feed方法返回，但
right here I'm going to say dot filter
在这里我要说点过滤器
and I'll say stock info over here and
我会在这里说股票信息
then I'll say in this case stock info
那我就说这种情况下的股票信息
dot value that I'm going to get from Ed
我将从Ed获得的点值
is let's say greater than 40 so we can
假设大于40，所以我们可以
immediately say well when the observable
当观察到的时候马上说好
is going to start emitting data towards
将会开始向发射数据
me
我
I can take the data the observable is
我可以观察到的数据是
emitting and I can start filtering the
发射，我可以开始过滤
data that gets emitted right here let's
在这里发出的数据让我们
see why there was no too happy about it
看看为什么没有那么高兴
so I can start filtering and I can say
所以我可以开始过滤，我可以说
stock info and then I can say stock info
股票信息，然后我可以说股票信息
dot value is greater than let's say $50
点值大于$ 50
and then you can say I'm going to start
然后你可以说我要开始了
emitting data but only if the data is
发出数据，但仅当数据为
I'm going to send data only the data is
我将仅发送数据
greater than add value not otherwise now
比增加价值更大，现在不是
the beauty is you can take this seed but
美丽是你可以拿这个种子，但是
you can put multiple intermediaries that
您可以放置​​多个中介
are observables to what's upstream but
可以观察到上游的情况，但是
they themselves become observables to
他们自己成为观察者
what is downstream so on one hand they
下游是什么，所以一方面
are observing on the other hand they can
另一方面，他们可以观察
become observables downstream as well
在下游也可以观察到
and they can start filtering things as
他们可以开始过滤内容为
you can see no price now is less than
您现在看不到任何价格都低于
$550
$ 550
point likewise you can do other things
指出你也可以做其他事情
as well you may say okay bank add back
以及您可能会说好的银行加回去
would be really nice if you can give us
如果你能给我们的话会很好
a little discount on the price so we can
价格上有一点折扣，所以我们可以
say stock info now we can say stock info
现在说股票信息我们可以说股票信息
we could provide the stock info tower
我们可以提供股票信息塔
ticker but we could take the price given
股票报价，但我们可以接受给定的价格
to us the value rather and then we could
给我们的价值，然后我们可以
say 0.9 and you start getting a 10%
说0.9，你开始得到10％
discount on the price so you can see the
价格折扣，因此您可以看到
prices no longer or $800 much less than
价格不再或低于$ 800
that so we can have these kinds of
这样我们就可以拥有
intermediaries working really well but
中介机构运作得很好，但是
not only can we do this we can also get
我们不仅可以做到这一点，还可以
to a situation where we can nicely say
我们可以很好地说的情况
that I want to receive data but I don't
我想接收数据但我不想要
want to be bothered by a lot of data so
想要被很多数据困扰
you could say something along the lines
你可以说些什么
of you could say a dark take and I'm
你们可能会说一个黑暗的选择，我
gonna say let's say five so this says I
要说五个，这就是说
only like to take five pieces of data
只喜欢拿五块数据
and don't bother with me any more data
别再烦我了
once it doesn't spin filter and take
一旦它不旋转过滤器并采取
well filter is kind of like a little
好过滤器有点像
slap it will block a data and say can go
一巴掌它会阻止数据并说可以
through or would let some data go
通过或会让一些数据通过
through so per data it might block or
通过这样，每个数据可能会阻塞或
release think of a cake as like valve so
释放想起蛋糕就像阀门
it is open to begin with the data keeps
它是开放的，从数据保存开始
going but when the condition is reached
去，但当条件达到
the wild closes up and no more data will
荒野封闭，不再有数据
go through in fact it's a little bit
经历了一点
more than that the take isn't observable
远不止于此
that will start transmitting data in
这将开始在
other words it will talk so whatever
换句话说，它会说话，所以无论
data is Bank Ryan being transmitted will
数据是瑞安银行正在传输
go past it but when the condition is met
经过它，但是当条件满足时
it is going to send an unsubscribe
它将发送退订
upstream and it'll send a complete
上游，它将发送完整的
downstream so notice in this case when I
下游，所以在这种情况下，当我
run this once the value five is reached
一旦达到值五，运行此命令
the the cake is going to take the
蛋糕要拿了
responsibility of transmitting a
传送一个
complete signal notice that done came
完整的信号通知已完成
actually from the take sending a
实际上是从发送
complete signal and that is already
完整的信号，那已经是
baked and well the take of course is
烤好了当然
going to give us only an ability to take
只会给我们一种能力
on five data but it could be pretty
在五个数据上，但可能很漂亮
logical as well you could do a take
逻辑也可以
while and you can say that
一会儿，你可以说
while this condition is true keep
当此条件为真时，请保持
sending data when that condition is not
在没有这种情况时发送数据
true anymore stop so in this case you
真的不再了，所以在这种情况下，您
can say keep sending me data until a
可以说继续向我发送数据，直到
certain stock prices this value but the
一定的股票价格这个值，但是
minute it reaches a threshold quit
达到阈值退出的分钟
sending me data I don't want to hear
向我发送我不想听到的数据
this anymore you can be very logical
这样你可以很合逻辑了
about it likewise you could take do it
关于它，你也可以做
not only a take while you could also do
不仅花了一点时间，你也可以做
a skip and a skip while as well and then
跳过，然后跳过，然后
you can be the opposite of what it take
你可能会相反
is doing so but then of course this
正在这样做，但是当然
works great but when you have multiple
效果很好，但是当您有多个
observers how things actually work well
观察者事情实际上如何运作
this is where a difference between water
这是水之间的区别
called hot observables and cold
称为热观测和冷
observables come in a cold observable is
可观察到的东西可悲的是
the default a cold observable will
默认是冷可观察到的
maintain multiple sessions concurrently
同时维护多个会话
so in other words with Leo subscribes to
所以换句话说，狮子座订阅了
my my observable I'm going to be
我的观察到我将成为
transmitting to Leo at the same time
同时传送给狮子座
when Sarah subscribes that's a
当莎拉订阅时，
completely separate session so in other
完全独立的会话，因此在其他会话中
words it's like me messaging I'll be on
像我这样的消息，我将继续
a message session with my wife a friend
和我老婆一个朋友的信息交流会
of mine may join in I'm gonna have two
的我可能会加入，我将有两个
distinctive sessions I'll say stuff to
我会说一些独特的会议
my wife and I'll say different stuff to
我的妻子和我会说不同的话
my friend they both are in completely do
我的朋友，他们俩都在做
two different messaging sessions I am a
我是两个不同的消息传递会话
cold observable on the other hand it is
另一方面，它是冷的
possible that my wife is chatting with
可能我老婆正在聊天
me when one of my son's come along and I
我，当我儿子之一来时，我
might decide the topics of common
可能决定共同的话题
interest I may put them together on a
兴趣，我可以将它们放在一起
message now I become what's called hot
现在的消息，我成为所谓的热门
observable because both my children and
可以观察到，因为我的孩子和
my wife can participate in the same
我老婆可以参加
conversation with me I maintain one
与我交谈我保持一个
session not multiple sessions so we can
会话没有多个会话，因此我们可以
have these kinds of distinctions between
之间有这些区别
if all the observer observers are
如果所有的观察者都是
viewing the same thing from the
从中查看同一件事
observable or are they having
可观察到的还是他们有
distinctive sessions we can manage that
独特的会议，我们可以管理
also very effectively as the case may be
视情况而定也非常有效
but not only that we say okay this is
但不仅我们说好，这是
all great but what if the observer is
一切都很好，但是如果观察者是
transmitting data at a certain phase and
在某个阶段传输数据，以及
the subscriber the observer is not able
订户观察者无法
to keep up with it what are we going to
跟上它，我们要做什么
do well this is where what is
做得好，这是哪里
called back pressure comes in so a back
叫做背压，所以背
pressure is where you can configure how
压力是您可以配置方式的地方
the system is going to respond when the
当
rate of transmission changes suddenly so
传播率突然改变，所以
there are a couple of different options
有两种不同的选择
one one back pressure is back pressure
一一背压就是背压
drop meaning I don't care I'll be
一滴意味着我不在乎我会
processing at my pace if the day is too
如果今天过得太快，我会按照自己的节奏进行处理
fast just get rid of the data when I'm
快摆脱掉数据，当我
ready I'll get the next data there are
准备好，我将获得下一个数据
some situations where that is the right
在某些情况下这是正确的
thing to do there are other times when
还有其他时间要做的事情
you want to buffer the data so there's
您想要缓冲数据，所以
an on back pressure buffer which will
一个背压缓冲器，它将
put the data into a buffer and you can
将数据放入缓冲区，您可以
be pulling the data out and processing
正在提取数据并进行处理
it at your pace while the data keeps
在数据保持不变的情况下按您的步调
streaming in and gets buffered again of
流进并再次缓冲
course that only makes sense if there
当然只有在那才有意义
are peak periods and non peak periods
是高峰期和非高峰期
where you can recover and start
您可以在那里恢复并开始
processing data so these trying to
处理数据，所以这些试图
produce you can also do what's called
产生你也可以做所谓的
throttling where you can start rattling
在哪里可以开始嘎嘎作响
and saying I don't want to be getting
并说我不想得到
this data at this pace I want to Eddy
这个数据我想以埃迪的速度
the pace at which I get the data there
我在那里获取数据的速度
could be a lot of noise from this and
可能由此产生很多噪音，
then when their data settles down I want
然后当他们的数据稳定下来时
to receive it one example of throttling
接受节流的一个例子
is where you are let's say observing
就是你说的观察
somebody typing on the keyboard
有人在键盘上打字
my wife says I'm extremely good and
我太太说我很好
typing back spaces well that's kind of
很好地键入空格
annoying right because we type in and we
令人讨厌的权利，因为我们输入了
delete type and delete type in delete
删除类型和删除中的删除类型
and you could say why don't I let the
你可以说为什么我不让
user type and stabilize what they really
用户类型并稳定他们的真实身份
type then I would take what they type
然后输入我要输入的内容
and process that that's when you could
然后就可以处理
be using things like throttling where
在诸如节流的地方使用
you give them opportunity for the noise
你给他们机会去吵闹
to settle down and then you can process
安定下来，然后您就可以处理
the data all of those approaches come in
所有这些方法的数据
really really handy so to summarize what
真的很方便，所以总结一下
we talked about the idea behind reactive
我们谈到了反应性背后的想法
programming is to be able to really
编程才能真正
create a system with elastic message
用弹性消息创建系统
driven very responsive and also very
驱动非常敏感，也非常
resilient and there are so many
有弹性，有很多
different solutions hopefully this gives
希望有不同的解决方案
you an idea about what we active
您对我们活跃的想法
programming is all about if you're
编程就是一切
interested in not going to record
有兴趣不去录音
examples I showed you here they are
我在这里展示给你看的例子
located at that URL on my downloads page
位于我的下载页面上的URL
I hope you found that useful
我希望你觉得有用
[Music]
[音乐]